DARIT DOBGIMA MBOTIJI



CONTACT

daritdope@gmail.com

(+971) 524526480

Dubai Marina

Date of Birth: 16/04/1998

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

07/2018

Basics of Cybersecurity

The Open University

10/2018

Course - Big Data

Queensland University of Technology
Queensland

From data to decisions

07/2014

GCE ADVANCED LEVEL

PSS BAFUT

07/2012

SUMMARY

Creative Photographer with record of accomplishment in producing attractive and technically strong imagery. Customizes approaches based on project or client requirements, medium and planned use. Expert in composition and editing. Personable and dedicated Customer Service Representative with extensive experience in Visual arts industry. Solid team player with upbeat, positive attitude and proven skill in establishing rapport with clients. Motivated to maintain customer satisfaction and contribute to company success. Articulate, enthusiastic and results-oriented with demonstrated passion for building relationships, cultivating partnerships and growing businesses. User-minded Web Developer prioritizes usability and adaptability during projects. Designs sites and apps to attract users with aesthetically pleasing interfaces and exceptional UX elements. Comfortable working within large-scale collaborations or on individually-developed assets.

SKILLS

- Image Editing
- Service-Oriented
- Creative Thinking
- Service Oriented
- Customer Service
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Team Training
- Phone and Email Etiquette
- Verbal and Written
 Communication
- Photography and Videography
- Payment Processing

- Complaint Resolution
- Website Analytics Tools
- Avid Learner
- Analytical Thinking
- Social Media
- WordPress Proficiency
- Search Engine Optimization
- Website Privacy and Security
- Website Maintenance
- Google Analytics
- Ecommerce Integration

GCE Ordinary Level

PSS Bafut Cameroon

LANGUAGES



EXPERIENCE

Google Ads Manager Self Employed Web | Dubai, UAE

11/2020 - Current

- Managed campaign development, creative designs and ad tracking.
- Developed attractive and engaging print and digital ads
- Devised updates to company online presence, including main business website.
- Gathered and evaluated promotional data to improve future planning.
- Created and implemented rules, contracts and revenue-generating plans for each contest or sweepstakes.
- Measured and reported on marketing campaign performance, gained insights and compared results against goals to identify strengths and weaknesses.
- Analyzed consumer behaviors and market trends, adjusting email and advertising campaigns based on current knowledge.
- Identified, implemented and enhanced marketing strategies by accounting for factors such as organizational objectives, market trends and costs.
- Aligned activities with corporate objectives by coordinating marketing, sales and IT processes.

SEO Expert Self Employed Web | Dubai, UAE

10/2020 - Current

- Devised strategies to correct SEO underperformance and resultantly increase traffic and visibility.
- Executed SEO functions such as keyword research, data collection, link optimization and site auditing.
- Performed keyword research and competitive analysis to identify effective strategies to meet client goals.
- Analyzed traffic and conversion trends and developed strategies to improve traffic.
- Developed SEO strategy, defined goals and prioritized tests and projects.

- Monitored and reported on key performance indicators and shared results with management team.
- Served as technical expert for site audits, performance analysis and troubleshooting.
- Optimized global brand performance in organic search engine results.
- Built high-ranking backlinks for growing e-commerce businesses through quality, SEO-driven articles.
- Served as main point of contact for clients, answering questions and responding to messages.
- Identified trends through assessment of competitor activities.
- Tracked website analytics and reported findings to clients.

Web Developer Self-employeed | Dubai, UAE

06/2019 - Current

- Designed websites, portals and large-scale web applications for multiple clients.
- Collaborated with UI and UX personnel to develop friendly and usable websites and web-based software.
- Increased web traffic by improving navigation, creating dynamic media sections and adding social media plugins.
- Tested and maintained core product software to provide optimization and reliable functionality for end users.
- Collaborated with colleagues across WordPress, ExpressionEngine and Magento.

Video and Picture Editor Steelhouse | Dubai, UAE

10/2017 - 02/2020

- Edited video by adding graphics, titles, audio and special effects.
- Analyzed video content for quality control and editorial corrections.
- Completed sound design, sequence selection and compression for post-production purposes.

- Checked video for corruption and confirmed media rendered correctly.
- Uploaded final cuts to content management systems and client platforms.
- Collaborated with creative team and director to ensure alignment between artistic vision and editing requirements.
- Collected data from camera media, transcoded video and audio files and managed file backup systems.
- Assembled professional lighting and photography equipment to produce product and head shot photographs.
- Maintained camera and photography equipment and performed repairs.
- Managed digital archives of photographs, organized files and protected against loss.
- Edited digital images lightly or with advanced techniques to create desired effects.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Hi, I'm Darit. A 23 year old Cameroonian video editor. I love everything that has to do with visual arts and i feel a true devotion for typography. I have over 5 years of experience working as a freelance graphic designer, web developer & photo and video editing and I'm always willing and & ready to collaborate with people who have as much passion for visual arts.

LANGUAGES

English

Other language(s)

French

Spanish